Cassio Cardoso (he/him)

Senior Front-end Software Engineer

Berlin, Germany <u>Email</u> I <u>Site</u> I <u>GitHub</u>

I am a passionate and self-motivated front-end software engineer with more than 8 years of experience. I love to craft great user experiences in the most efficient and elegant way. I am completely enthusiastic with a full-stack environment and passionate about the JavaScript world.

SKILLS

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Redux, Webpack, TypeScript, Node.js, Express, Next.js, GraphQL, Google Cloud (Firebase, Firestore, PubSub, Cloud Functions)

EXPERIENCE

Vimcar, Germany - Senior Software Engineer

07/2020 - PRESENT

Working in the internal tooling team our main focus is to provide tools and infrastructure for the other teams at Vimcar.

- Development of new internal tools for our stakeholders (sales; customer service; etc).
- Defining standards for the front-end development for the whole company (common patterns; shared libraries; design system).
- Acting as the scrum master for the team and driving the scrum rituals.

Omio, Germany - Software Engineer

11/2018 - 06/2020

Worked in the acquisition tribe where our main goal was to get more users on the platform and convert them into customers by providing the best experiences tailored to their intent.

- Created new components tailored to the user intent for the landing pages.
- Developed an MVP of the AMP pages project to speed up the landing pages.
- Worked on performance metrics and monitoring to optimize the landing pages' speed KPIs.
- Acted as the scrum master for the team and driving the scrum rituals.
- Acted as the technical leader in some projects and mentored junior developers.

QuintoAndar, Brazil - Software Engineer

11/2017 - 10/2018

Worked in the agents squad where our main mission was to migrate a native Android app to a PWA, so the real estate agents could use it in any platform.

- Created the PWA from scratch.
- Created and maintained performance budgets for the app.
- Developed the back-end for the project using Node.js + TypeScript and Google Firestore.
- Developed jobs using Airflow, Kafka and Google Pub Sub to sync data between different services.

Amaro, Brazil - Lead Front-end Engineer

07/2014 - 10/2017

Worked as the lead front-end engineer and was involved in hiring, mentoring and managing front-end engineers in the team. Participated in OKRs definitions and project prioritization with stakeholders.

- Organized the front-end team tasks in an agile way.
- Recruiting and people management: One-on-ones, performance reviews, mentoring younger developers.
- Developed the e-commerce front-end application from scratch
- Developed the internal UI framework.

EDUCATION

UNIVAP, Brazil - Computer Engineering

GRADUATED IN 2014

PROJECTS

FEMUG-VP (Front-end meetup group), Brazil - Co-founder

I helped to organize the Front-end developers' community in my home town. We organized meetups and events to share knowledge and discuss front-end related topics.

VOLUNTEERING

Taubaté Big Donkeys, Brazil - Founder & President

I founded an american football team in my home town called Taubaté Big Donkeys. The team is a non-profit organization which aims to teach flag football and american football to teenagers and adults in the city. The team also played in regional competitions organized by the Brazilian american football association.

^^^^